<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Script Adults</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Script Adults</description>
    <image>
      <title>Script Adults</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.128.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 23:10:42 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[Updated 20250301]Centrality: how we actually perceive the severity of a bug</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/security/centrality-what-cvss-missed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 02:59:19 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/security/centrality-what-cvss-missed/</guid>
      <description>Info
Updates:
After giving a second thought on the topic and reorganizing the materials, I had a sharing session with my teammates and decided to update this article accordingly. Updates include more suitable examples and graphics.
An empty business lingo or a good quantification? We hope to, and probably need to, quantify the severity of security bugs. The “need” mainly comes from the fact that we have to provide an interface to management: We need to have a reasonably objective quantification to tell how serious an issue is (and show that we would not overplay/downplay something for our own self-interest), and that would lay the groundwork for the establishment of a bug handling standard that the engineering team would follow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Picking grammatical mistakes in an insightful article</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/picking-grammatical-mistakes-in-an-insightful-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:15:38 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/picking-grammatical-mistakes-in-an-insightful-article/</guid>
      <description>After the huge attention gained by deepseek R1, I have seen a good amount of people immediately went to looking for censorships (which are expected to exist), laughed at it, and looked down on it. They totally missed the points and these behaviors made them look like slaves of their very own defense mechanism1.
Deepseek did make some techonological breakthroughs. Indeed the censorship is a defect of such a great product.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Added tikzjax support</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/meta/added-tikzjax-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 17:37:38 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/meta/added-tikzjax-support/</guid>
      <description>Just added support for tikzjax since I received some feedback about my hand-drawn diagrams are hard to read&amp;hellip;now I can use nice graphs like these:
source: https://tikzjax.com/ source: https://tikzjax.com/ source: https://tikz.net/ source: https://tikz.net/ </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our legal (and moral) system flavors the jerks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/our-legal-and-moral-system-flavors-jerks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 23:50:58 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/our-legal-and-moral-system-flavors-jerks/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: The author&amp;rsquo;s knowledge about the legal system by no means applies to anywhere outside of his homeland. But what is legal or illegal should be similar enough for the discussion below - at least for first world countries, I guess.
That said, the author is not a lawyer and does not have accurate knowledge of any concrete laws. But one does not need to know (too many of) them for this article.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why use binary search when you can guess where it should be</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/computer-science/why-use-binary-search-when-you-can-guess-where-it-should-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 23:40:23 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/computer-science/why-use-binary-search-when-you-can-guess-where-it-should-be/</guid>
      <description>Why ignore 50% of what we know about the data1 Everyone learnt binary search in Algo 101. It is the fastest way (among comparison based searches) to find an element in a sorted array. All you need to carry out the algorithms is the comparison between the target element and the element at the current position. It is widely applicable because it assumes so little from the data. But for many real life problems, we do often know something apart from merely the comparison between the two numbers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Work at the level of abstraction that works for you</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/level-of-abstraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:20:01 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/level-of-abstraction/</guid>
      <description>Ladder of abstraction Well the title is obviously a tweak of the &amp;ldquo;ladder of abstraction&amp;rdquo;. For those who does not know, &amp;ldquo;ladder of abstraction&amp;rdquo; refers to the classic essay by Bret Victor. I am kind of stealing this terminilogy for the reader to visualize climbing up and down on the ladder of abstraction to make it easier to explain the nature of different jobs. The main question this blog post deals with is:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relaxation is the result of mastery. With thoughts about problem solving</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/relaxation-is-the-result-of-mastery-with-thoughts-about-problem-solving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:37:21 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/relaxation-is-the-result-of-mastery-with-thoughts-about-problem-solving/</guid>
      <description>Relaxation as a result of mastery, instead of a prerequisites In many sports/ crafts that I have experienced, relaxation is considered by many the prerequisites of mastery:
In playing piano, your fingers, wrists, arms and shoulders have to be relax or you will find it extremely hard to press the right keys fluently; In online games that require fast reactions, rookies hands are stiff and they press buttons with unnecessary strength and range of motion, which stops them from pressing right buttons at the right time smoothly; In jiujitsu, being reasonably relax helps you to perform efficient moves, saving your energy and gives you more choices in different situations in which you have to adapt and react quickly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reinventing Catalan numbers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/mathematics/reinventing-catalan-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 17:59:01 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/mathematics/reinventing-catalan-numbers/</guid>
      <description>Counting binary trees I was thinking about of the problem of balancing a binary tree, and my mind stumbled across to the question &amp;ldquo;How many different binary trees with labelled nodes can you make without changing the traversal order?&amp;rdquo;. After figuring out the answer myself I realized that the numbers of such binary trees are just Catalan numebrs (I was not really into combinatorics - now I am).
For example, the following has traversal order 1-&amp;gt;2-&amp;gt;3-&amp;gt;4-&amp;gt;5-&amp;gt;6-&amp;gt;7</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From casual description of Turing Machine to the density of uncomputable functions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/computer-science/from-casual-description-of-turing-machine-to-uncompuatble-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 01:23:55 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/computer-science/from-casual-description-of-turing-machine-to-uncompuatble-functions/</guid>
      <description>Defining the machine by describing it In Sipser&amp;rsquo;s Introduction to the theory of computation, a alternative way of defining a Turing machine (other than defining the formal 7-tuple, which is a PITA) - by its &amp;ldquo;description&amp;rdquo;. Example (from the proof of $A_{TM}$ is deciable):
M = “On input &amp;lt;B, w&amp;gt;, where B is a DFA and w is a string: 1. Simulate B on input w. 2. If the simulation ends in an accept state, accept .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why do I hate using chatGPT to replace search engines</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/why-do-i-hate-chatgpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 23:39:11 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/why-do-i-hate-chatgpt/</guid>
      <description>My pc is overheated how do i cool it down because it is my life1 Someone said that chatGPT will replace Google. Some kids/ early teenagers do often ask chatGPT for things that could have been found by Googling.
I really hate the idea of replacing search engines by chatGPT. The problem I have with it is not really about AI, but about how do we interact with it.
When we were kids and learnt how to use search engines, we acquired the skills of capturing important parts of the questions in our minds and turn them into keywords.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unity Game Reversing(1): Setup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/security/unity-game-reversing-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 04:16:55 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/security/unity-game-reversing-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Recently I am trying to reverse engineering a simple Windows desktop game made with Unity. I took a look on some reference but found that the setup can be a bit frustrating. This post is attempting to make the setup clearer and more followable. Reference links are listed below.
Tools Our target is to decompile and debug the Assembly-CSharp.dll inside the folder &amp;lt;game root folder&amp;gt;\&amp;lt;GANE_NAME&amp;gt;_Data\Managed\, which contains custom code the game developer wrote, not the code of Unity or other frameworks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LOTS Project - Paypal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/security/lots-project-paypal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 00:54:30 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/security/lots-project-paypal/</guid>
      <description>Introduction LOTS project, founded by mrd0x, is a collection of websites which is likely be trusted but can be used to evade detection when conducting phishing, C&amp;amp;C, exfiltration and downloading tools. In this post I will introduce a way to abusing PayPal and hopefully will be contributing to the LOTS project.
This series is (intentively) for my ideas on novel exfiltration/ C&amp;amp;C channels.
Exfiltraftion by Paypal In Paypal, one can dispute an order and upload his/ her evidence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prisma Cloud Defenders</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/security/prisma-cloud-defenders/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 17:54:24 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/security/prisma-cloud-defenders/</guid>
      <description>Tl;dr - unfixed information disclosure in Prisma Cloud defenders This post is about how to abuse a agent of a cloud security solution to get information which you should not know, like what security controls are applied, what assets the victim owns and the owners of the assets.
Introduction A few months ago I was examining the Prisma Cloud configuration of my workplace and accidentally discovered an information disclosure issue of Prisma Cloud defender (the agent).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/wtever-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/wtever-law/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
