<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Thoughts on Script Adults</title><link>https://katsuragicsl.github.io/categories/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in Thoughts on Script Adults</description><image><title>Script Adults</title><url>https://katsuragicsl.github.io/images/papermod-cover.png</url><link>https://katsuragicsl.github.io/images/papermod-cover.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.128.2</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 15:02:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://katsuragicsl.github.io/categories/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Relaxation is the result of mastery. With thoughts about problem solving</title><link>https://katsuragicsl.github.io/blogs/thoughts/relaxation-is-the-result-of-mastery-with-thoughts-about-problem-solving/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:37:21 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://katsuragicsl.github.io/blogs/thoughts/relaxation-is-the-result-of-mastery-with-thoughts-about-problem-solving/</guid><description>Relaxation as a result of mastery, instead of a prerequisites In many sports/ crafts that I have experienced, relaxation is considered by many the prerequisites of mastery:
In playing piano, your fingers, wrists, arms and shoulders have to be relax or you will find it extremely hard to press the right keys fluently; In online games that require fast reactions, rookies hands are stiff and they press buttons with unnecessary strength and range of motion, which stops them from pressing right buttons at the right time smoothly; In jiujitsu, being reasonably relax helps you to perform efficient moves, saving your energy and gives you more choices in different situations in which you have to adapt and react quickly.</description></item><item><title>Why do I hate using chatGPT to replace search engines</title><link>https://katsuragicsl.github.io/blogs/thoughts/why-do-i-hate-chatgpt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 23:39:11 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://katsuragicsl.github.io/blogs/thoughts/why-do-i-hate-chatgpt/</guid><description>My pc is overheated how do i cool it down because it is my life1 Someone said that chatGPT will replace Google. Some kids/ early teenagers do often ask chatGPT for things that could have been found by Googling.
I really hate the idea of replacing search engines by chatGPT. The problem I have with it is not really about AI, but about how do we interact with it.
When we were kids and learnt how to use search engines, we acquired the skills of capturing important parts of the questions in our minds and turn them into keywords.</description></item></channel></rss>