<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Philosophy on Script Adults</title><link>https://katsuragicsl.github.io/tags/philosophy/</link><description>Recent content in Philosophy on Script Adults</description><image><title>Script Adults</title><url>https://katsuragicsl.github.io/images/papermod-cover.png</url><link>https://katsuragicsl.github.io/images/papermod-cover.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.128.2</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 23:10:42 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://katsuragicsl.github.io/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[Updated 20250301]Centrality: how we actually perceive the severity of a bug</title><link>https://katsuragicsl.github.io/blogs/security/centrality-what-cvss-missed/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 02:59:19 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://katsuragicsl.github.io/blogs/security/centrality-what-cvss-missed/</guid><description>Info
Updates:
After giving a second thought on the topic and reorganizing the materials, I had a sharing session with my teammates and decided to update this article accordingly. Updates include more suitable examples and graphics.
An empty business lingo or a good quantification? We hope to, and probably need to, quantify the severity of security bugs. The “need” mainly comes from the fact that we have to provide an interface to management: We need to have a reasonably objective quantification to tell how serious an issue is (and show that we would not overplay/downplay something for our own self-interest), and that would lay the groundwork for the establishment of a bug handling standard that the engineering team would follow.</description></item><item><title>Our legal (and moral) system flavors the jerks</title><link>https://katsuragicsl.github.io/blogs/thoughts/our-legal-and-moral-system-flavors-jerks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 23:50:58 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://katsuragicsl.github.io/blogs/thoughts/our-legal-and-moral-system-flavors-jerks/</guid><description>Disclaimer: The author&amp;rsquo;s knowledge about the legal system by no means applies to anywhere outside of his homeland. But what is legal or illegal should be similar enough for the discussion below - at least for first world countries, I guess.
That said, the author is not a lawyer and does not have accurate knowledge of any concrete laws. But one does not need to know (too many of) them for this article.</description></item></channel></rss>