<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on Script Adults</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughts on Script Adults</description>
    <image>
      <title>Script Adults</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.128.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 01:54:52 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The true talent is the ability to carry on</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/true-talent-is-carry-on-with-passion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:03:17 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/true-talent-is-carry-on-with-passion/</guid>
      <description>Long time ago I read a quote from Habu1(as shown in the screenshot):
The true talent is the ability to carry on with passion, even when it probably won&amp;rsquo;t pay off.
(not translated word by word)
I was a teenager and it did not make any sense to me. How could passion be the true talent? Look at those geniuses like Gauss, Mozart, John von Neumann! What they have done is not something that could have been done by normal people.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Picking grammatical mistakes in an insightful article</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/picking-grammatical-mistakes-in-an-insightful-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:15:38 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/picking-grammatical-mistakes-in-an-insightful-article/</guid>
      <description>After the huge attention gained by deepseek R1, I have seen a good amount of people immediately went to looking for censorships (which are expected to exist), laughed at it, and looked down on it. They totally missed the points and these behaviors made them look like slaves of their very own defense mechanism1.
Deepseek did make some techonological breakthroughs. Indeed the censorship is a defect of such a great product.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our legal (and moral) system flavors the jerks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/our-legal-and-moral-system-flavors-jerks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 23:50:58 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/our-legal-and-moral-system-flavors-jerks/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: The author&amp;rsquo;s knowledge about the legal system by no means applies to anywhere outside of his homeland. But what is legal or illegal should be similar enough for the discussion below - at least for first world countries, I guess.
That said, the author is not a lawyer and does not have accurate knowledge of any concrete laws. But one does not need to know (too many of) them for this article.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Work at the level of abstraction that works for you</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/level-of-abstraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:20:01 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/level-of-abstraction/</guid>
      <description>Ladder of abstraction Well the title is obviously a tweak of the &amp;ldquo;ladder of abstraction&amp;rdquo;. For those who does not know, &amp;ldquo;ladder of abstraction&amp;rdquo; refers to the classic essay by Bret Victor. I am kind of stealing this terminilogy for the reader to visualize climbing up and down on the ladder of abstraction to make it easier to explain the nature of different jobs. The main question this blog post deals with is:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relaxation is the result of mastery. With thoughts about problem solving</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/relaxation-is-the-result-of-mastery-with-thoughts-about-problem-solving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:37:21 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/relaxation-is-the-result-of-mastery-with-thoughts-about-problem-solving/</guid>
      <description>Relaxation as a result of mastery, instead of a prerequisites In many sports/ crafts that I have experienced, relaxation is considered by many the prerequisites of mastery:
In playing piano, your fingers, wrists, arms and shoulders have to be relax or you will find it extremely hard to press the right keys fluently; In online games that require fast reactions, rookies hands are stiff and they press buttons with unnecessary strength and range of motion, which stops them from pressing right buttons at the right time smoothly; In jiujitsu, being reasonably relax helps you to perform efficient moves, saving your energy and gives you more choices in different situations in which you have to adapt and react quickly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why do I hate using chatGPT to replace search engines</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/why-do-i-hate-chatgpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 23:39:11 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/thoughts/why-do-i-hate-chatgpt/</guid>
      <description>My pc is overheated how do i cool it down because it is my life1 Someone said that chatGPT will replace Google. Some kids/ early teenagers do often ask chatGPT for things that could have been found by Googling.
I really hate the idea of replacing search engines by chatGPT. The problem I have with it is not really about AI, but about how do we interact with it.
When we were kids and learnt how to use search engines, we acquired the skills of capturing important parts of the questions in our minds and turn them into keywords.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
